Bisbee Deportation Legal Papers and Exhibits 1917-1919
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Bisbee Deportation Legal Papers and Exhibits 1917-1919
AZ 114
Unknown
The Bisbee Deportation Legal Papers and Exhibits collection consists of photostats of legal papers and exhibits pertaining to the suit of Michael Simmons vs. the El Paso and Southwestern Railroad Company et al. in the Superior Court of Cochise County.
1.2 Linear Feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://www.library.arizona.edu/speccoll
Restrictions
None
Historical Note
In the early 1900's Bisbee was a boom town controlled by mining companies. By 1917 the price of copper had increased due to World War I, leading to enormous prfits for companies and their shareholders. Union activity was becoming more and more prevalent in mining communities during this period. The International Workers of the World (I.W.W.) had been actively recruiting miners, and on June 24, 1917 sent a list of demands to the Bisbee mining companies. The demands included safer working condidiotns, a fixed wage instead of a sliding scale wage, and an end to discrimintation of foreign and minority workers. All demands were rejected, and as a result, a strike was called. Over half of Bisbee's miners went on strike. The deprotation occurred on July 12, 1917 when Sheriff Harry C. Wheeler led a vigilante group that rounded up 1,186 men (some of whom were not even strikers) and abandoned them at Hermans, New Mexico. Guards surrounded the town to prevent the deportees from returning. Others perceived as disloyal were tried and faced deportation as well. On July 14, government troops escorted the miners to Columbus where they continued to be held. Several months later, the Federal Mediation Commission set up by President Wilson, found that the mining companies were at fault in the deportation. However, they also found that no federal laws applied to the actions and referred the matter to the state of Arizona. Although the state took no action, several civil suits were brought by the deportees against the mining companies were settled out of court. All but one suit brought against individual vigilantes were dismissed. The one suit that went to trial ended in a not guilty verdict. The Bisbee Deportation had a lasting influence throughout the United States.
Arrangement
This collection is organized by case and legal exhibit followed by individual items.
Scope and Content Note
Includes materials from 1916-1920. Exhibits presented in the suit of Michael Simmons vs. the El Paso and Wouthwestern Railroad Co. et al. The exhibits include photostatic copies of correspondence of hte I.W.W. and I. W. W. leaflets. They also include original I.W.W. pamphlets and one photograph. The list items contain the exhibit number, the name of the item, the author, the number of pages, and the date, where available. In the case of pamphlets, full bibliographic reference is given. The exhibits in the Simmons vs. El Paso and Southwestern Rail Road suit are numbered from 1 through 181. The exhibits in the State of Arizona vs. Harry Walters are referred to as Butte Exhibit, Defendant's Exhibit, Salt Lake Exhibit, and Spokane Exhibit.
Access Terms
Industrial Workers of the World
Copper miners--History--Sources
Copper miners--Labor unions--Arizona--Bisbee
Strikes and lockouts--Copper mining--Arizona--Bisbee
Copper Miners' Strike, Arizona, 1917
Container List
- Simmons v. El Paso and Southwestern Rail Road Exhibits 1-17, 23, 28-50 1917
  - Exhibit 1. List of items taken from I.W.W. headqurters, 13pp, by Maurice Klein, 10/1/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 2. War prpaganda: 'Warning,' by I.W.W., 1p (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 4-7. I.W.W. stickers, 1p (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 8-12. I.W.W. sickers, 1p (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 13-17. I.W.W. stickers, 1p (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 28. Sign up sheet, 1p (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 29. Exhibit number and title, inventory, 2pp (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 30. Court document: William D. Haywood vs. U.S.A., 2pp, by Edward M. Holloway, 10/17/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 31. Letter to William D. Haywood from Grover H. Perry, 4pp, 2/17/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 32. Slip, written copy of quotations, 'Join the army or navy,' etc., 1p (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 33. Telegram to William D. Haywood from Grover Perry, 1p, 6/25/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 34. Telegram to William D. Haywood from Defense Committee, 1p, 6/17/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 35. Telegram to William D. Haywood from F.H. Little, 1p, 4/10/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 36. Telegram to Joe Astes from F.H. Little and William D. Haywood, 7pp, 7/6/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 37. Letters to Harry Llayd and William D. Haywood from Peter Rickman, 2pp, 6/5/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 38. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from Richard Brazier, 4pp, 2/4/1917; 2/9/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 39. Letter and reply to Jack Sheen from William Haywood, 4pp, 8/20/1917; 8/28/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 40. Letter to Arthur Le Seuer from General Sec'y Treas., 2pp, 6/13/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 41. Two letters, 2pp: To Socialist Publishing Bureau from Sec'y Treas. I.W.W., 8/13/1917; To William D. Haywood from A. Toivonen, 8/12/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 42. Letter and reply to Leon Shuff form William D. Haywood, 2pp, 5/29/1917; 6/1/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 43. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from John Pancner, 3pp, 1/10/1917; 2/14/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 44. I.W.W. membership book and letter to William D. Haywood form William Taeyh, 3pp, 8/1/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 45. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from Dan Buckley, 2pp, 7/3/1917; 7/7/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 46. Letter to fellow worker from P. McEvoy, 1p, 6/3/1917; 46. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 47. Letter to Harrison George from Grover H. Perry, 1p, 5/21/1917; 47. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits 48. Letter to William D. Haywood from Grover H Perry, 1p, 4/20/1917; 48. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 49. Letter and reply to Joe Gordon and Elmer Groves form William D. Haywood, 2pp, 4/11/1917; 4/13/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit 50. Letter to F.H. Little from William D. Haywood, 1p, 7/27/1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Simmons v. El Paso and Southwestern Rail Road Exhibits 18-27 1916-1917
  - Exhibit 18. Preamble and Constitution of the International Workers of the World (Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, [1916?]) 32pp (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Exhibit 19. Vincent St. John, The I.W.W. Its History, Structure and Methods (Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1917) 32pp (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Exhibit 20. Abner E. Woodruff, The Advancing Proletariat (Chicago: I.W.W. Pupblishing Bureau, 1917) 32pp (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Exhibit 21. Austin Lewis, Proletarian and Petit-Bourgeois (Chicago: I.W.W. Pupblishing Bureau, [no date]) 48pp. Also contains: Charles Edward Russel, "What Comes of Playing the Game" and Scott Nearing, "Those Who Own And Those Who Work" (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Exhibit 22. William D. Haywood, The General Strike (Chicago: I.W.W. Pupblishing Bureau, [no date]) 48pp. Also contains: G.B., "The Last War," and "The Deadly Parallel" (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Exhibit 24. Gustave Hervé, Patriotism and the Worker (Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, [1912?]) 32pp (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Exhibit 25. Nils H. Hanson, The Onward Sweep of the Machine Process(Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, [no date]) 32pp. Also contains: T. Glynn, "Industrial Efficiency and its Antidote," and Barbara Lily Frankenthal, "The Diesel Motor" (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Exhibit 26. Industrial Workers of the World, Proceedings, 10th Convention, 1916 (Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1917) 160pp (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Exhibit 27. Joe Hill, I.W.W. Songs to Fan the Flames of Discontent, Joe Hill Memorial Edition (Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1917) 59pp (Box 1, Folder 1A)
- Simmons Vs. El Paso and Southwestern Rail Road Exhibits 51-116 1914-1917
  - Exhibit 51. Letter to William D. Haywood from F.H. Little, 1p, 4/16/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 52. Letter to William D. Haywood from Grover H. Perry, 1p, 4/16/1917; 52. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 53. Statement of the Executive Board of the I.W.W. on War, 1p (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 54. Letter to S. Bromberg from Gen. Sec'y Treas., 1p, 8/22/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 55. Three letters, 3pp: To Forrest Edwards form Gen. Sec'y Treas., 1/13/1916; To William D. Haywood from Forrest Edwards, 1/16/1916; To Ben H. Williams from Gen. Sec'y Treas., 1/13/1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 56.Letter to Hugh P. Gallagher from Gen. Sec'y Treas., 1p, 7/13/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 57. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from P. McEvoy, 2pp, 8/30/1917; 9/4/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 58. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from Margaret Ray, 3pp, 7/16/1917; 7/17/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 59. Two letters, 5pp: To William D. Haywood from J.M. Slovick, undated; To J.M. Slovick from William D. Haywood, 2/9/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 60. Two letters, 2pp: To Executive Committee, I.W.W. from Finnish Workers Defense League, 7/6/1917; To Sec'y of Workers Defense League from Sec'y Treas. of I.W.W., 7/9/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 61. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from Francis Miller, 4pp, 4/8/1917; 4/12/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 62. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from Eino Kuitunen, 3pp, 5/29/1917; 6/1/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 63. Letter to William D. Haywood from Civilian Camp Columbus, NM, 3pp, 6/25/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 64. Minutes: Gen. Executive Board Meeting, by Lambert, Recording Sec'y 6pp, 6/29-7/6/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 65. Letter to Grover H. Perry from M.C. Sullivan, 3pp (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 66. Letter to Grover H. Perry from E.J. MacCasham, 8pp, 4/21/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 67. Letter to Grover H. Perry from T.R. Wilson, 2pp, 7/9/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 68. Letter to Grover H. Perry from E.J. MacCasham, 3pp, 7/6/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 69. Letter to Grover H. Perry from E.J. MacCasham, 4pp, 7/19/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 70. Letter to Grover H. Perry form J.A. McDonald, 1p, 6/27/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exibit 71. Letter to Grover H. Perry from E.J. MacCasham, 4pp, 6/9/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 72. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Jack Norman, 3pp, 7/23/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibt 73. Letter to Geo Maddox from Jack Norman, 2pp, 8/7/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 74. Letter to Grover H. Perry from J. McDonald, 1p, 7/23/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 75. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Roger S. Culver, 2pp, 4/15/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 76. Letter to Ececutive Committee from Secretary-Treasurer, 2pp, 7/10/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 77. Letter Chas. H. MacKinnon from Secretary-Treasurer, 2pp, 6/5/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 78. Letter to F.H. Little from Secretary Treasurer, 3pp, 4/11/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 79. Memo from Grover H. Perry 1p, 6/1/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 80. Letter to Grover H. Pery from Jos. Oatis, 3pp, 7/6/1917; 80. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 81. Letter to Grover H. Pery from William D. Haywood, 2pp, 3/28/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 82. Letter to Grover H. Perry from A.S. Embre, 2pp, 7/26/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 83. Letter to Grover H. Perry from A.S. Embre, 2pp, 6/26/1917; 83. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 84. Letter to Grover H. Perry from J. MacDonald, 1p, 7/6/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 85. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Press committee, 1p, 7/6/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 86. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Roger S. Culver, 1p, 4/28/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 87. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Press committee, 1p, 7/4/1917; 87. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 88. Letter and reply to V.V. O'Hair from Jack Norman, 4pp, 8/18/1917; 8/24/1917; 88. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 89. Letter to Grover H. Perry from J. MacDonald, 1p, 7/2/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 90. Credentials of Grover H. Perry, by Willaim D. Haywood, 1p, 5/31/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 91. 9Dues card for Grover H. Perry, 1p, 3/20/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 92. Letter to Iron Industry Workers, 1p (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 93. Statement of Work by F.H. Little, 1p (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 94. Three letters, 4pp: To William D. Haywood from A.C. Christ 4/24/1917; To A.C. Christ from William D. Haywood, 4/28/1917; To A.C. Christ from William D. Haywood, 4/28/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 95. Letter to William D. Haywood from J. Cully, 6pp, 6/11/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 96. Letter to William D. Haywood from J. Cully, 3pp, 7/7/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 97. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from J. Cully, 3pp, 8/29/1917; 8/31/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 98. Letter and reply to William D. Haywood from J. Cully, 2pp, 4/25/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 99. Letter to J.D. Gould from Chas R. Jacobs, 1p, 7/5/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 100. Letter and reply to Don Sheridan from William D. Haywood, 3pp, 3/21/1917; 3/26/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 101. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Jack Norman, 1p, 7/30/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 102. Telegram to Editor Solidarity from J. Cully, 1p, 6/6/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 103. Letter to G.H. Bourg from C.L. Lambert, 1p, 7/29/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 104. Letter to William D. Haywood from C.L. Lambert, 1p, 6/10/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 105. Letter to fellow workers from C.L. Lambert, 1p (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 106. Letter to Thos.J. Dickson from C.L. Lambert, 1p, 8/5/1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibti 107. Letter to C.L. Lambert from William D. Haywood, 1p, 7/1/1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 108. Letter to Richard Smith from Thos. Whitehead, 1p, 8/7/1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 109. Letter to S.H. Dixon from Thos. Whitehead, 1p, 8/12/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 110. Letter to George Millard from Thos. Whitehead, 1p, 4/27/1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 111. Letter to William D. Haywood from The Strike Committee, 1p, 8/2/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 112. Letter to J.A. MacDonald from William D. Haywood, 1p, 2/6/1917; 112. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 113. Chemical prescriptions, "A few hints to active Saboteurs," 4pp (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 114. Telegram to W.H. Lewis from William D. Haywood, 1p, 7/26/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 115. I.W.W. circular, "Do you want a contract?" by Grover H. Perry, 1p (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit 116. Minutes: Meeting, by A.S. Embree, 3pp, 6/23/1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Simmons v. El Paso and Southwestern Rail Road Exhibits 117-125, 155, 160, 164-167, 169-178, 180-181 1917
  - Exhibit 117. Bulletin and minutes of Metal Mine Workers Industrial Union 800 convention, by Grover H. Perry, 5pp, 7/13/1917; 7/15-7/17/1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibti 118. Minutes of Lumberworkers Convention, by Geroge Herbert, Recording Secreatry, 6pp, 3/4-6/1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibti 119. Letter and reply to Don Sheridan from Grover H. Perry, 2pp, 4/11/1917; 4/17/1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 120. Chemical prescriptions, "How to make explosives," 1p (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Exhbit 121. Letter and reply to James Rowan from Albert Jahn, 3pp, 5/29/1917; 5/31/1917; 121. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 122. Letter and reply to James Rowan from Jos. Ratti, 2pp, 5/22/1917; 5/24/1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 123. Letter and reply to James Rowan from William Hardy, 2pp, 5/21/1917; 5/23/1917; 123. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 124. Minutes: Special Business Meeting, by H. Grant, Recording Secretary, 5pp, 3/18/1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 125. Application for Membership, 1p (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 155, 160, 164, 166. I.W.W. Stickers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 167-171. I.W.W. Stickers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 172-176. I.W.W. Stickers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 177-178. I.W.W. Stickers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 180. Black and white photographs of red banner displaying: "DOWN (or DAWN) With War" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit 181. List of items sent to Agent Clabaush, 2pp, 9/14/1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Simmons v. El Paso and Southwestern Rail Road Exhibits 127-129, 131-133, 1913-1917
  - Emile Pouget, Sabotage (Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, c1913), 130pp, 127. (Box 1, Folder 3A)
  - Exhibit 128. Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Sabotage (Cleveland, Ohio: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1916), 32pp (Box 1, Folder 3A)
  - Exhibit 129. André Tridon, The New Unionism (New York: B.W. Huebsch, 1917), 200pp (Box 1, Folder 3A)
  - Exhibit 131. Joseph J. Ettor, Industrial Unionism: The Road to Freedom [1913?], 32pp (Box 1, Folder 3A)
  - Exhibit 132. Grover H. Perry, The Revolutionary I.W.W. (Cleveland, Ohio: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1916), 32pp; Also contains: B.H. Williams, "The Constructive Program of the I.W.W.," and Grover H. Perry, "How Scabs Are Bred" (Box 1, Folder 3A)
  - Exhibit 133. Walker C. Smith, Sabotage: Its History, Philosophy and Function(Chicago: I.W.W. jPublishing Bureau, [1917]), 32pp (Box 1, Folder 3A)
- State of Arizona vs. H. Walters. Depositions [Byrn, Thomas], 1917-1919
  - Exhbit No. 2684 cover sheet, by Edward B. Howell, Notary Public, 1p, 12/5/1919 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Agreement to Depostitions No. 2684, by Court Reporter, 9/9/1919 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Butte Exhibit 1. Letter to Harry Llayd from Peter Rickman, 1p, 9/9/1919 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Butte Exhibit 2. Letter to William D. Haywood, 1p, 6/5/1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Butte Exhibit 3. I.W.W. circular "War is hell. We do not want it!", 1p (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Butte Exhibit 4. Black and white photograph of red banner displaying:"DOWN (or DAWN) With War" (Box 2, Folder 1)
- State of Arizona vs. H. Walters. Depositions [Daniels, Berridge, etc.], 1917-1919
  - Exhibit 2. No. 2684 Cover sheet, by Robert M. Gibboney, Notary Public, 1p, 11/26/1919 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Depositions No. 2684, 2685, 2686, 2687, 2688, 2689, 2725, by Court Reporter, 15pp, 10/17/1919 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Deposition No. 2684, by Court Reporter, 59pp, 10/17/1919 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Defendant's Exhibit 1. Letter to William D. Haywood from J. Cully, exhibit from deposition No. 2684, 6pp, 7/11/1917 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Defendant's Exhibit 2. Exhibit from deposition No. 2684 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Stat of Arizona vs. H. Walters. Depositions [Nebeker, Reinhardt], 1917-1920
  - No. 2684 cover sheet, by J.E. Jaures, Clerk, H.P Johnson, Deputy, 1p, 7/9/1920 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Deposition No. 2684 of Aquila Nebeker and Cecilia Reinhardt, by Court Clerk, 54pp, 12/1/1919 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 1. Property taken from Salt Lake, by Leon Bone, 9pp, 9/5/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 2. Cover sheet with name tag, 1p (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 3. List of items sent to Agent Clabaugh, 2pp, 9/14/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 4. I.W.W. Preamble and Constitution in Spanish, pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 5. I.W.W. Official Membership Book (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 6. Letter to V.V. O'Hair from Jack Norman, 3pp (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 7. Letter to Grover H. Perry from J. MacDonald, 1p, 7/2/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 8. Letter to Jack F. Norman from Sec'y Treas., 1p, 8/24/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 9. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Press Committee, 1p, 7/4/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 10. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Roger S. Culver, 1p, 4/28/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 11. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Press Committee, 1p, 7/5/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 12. Letter to Grover H. Perry from J. MacDonald, 1p, 7/6/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 13. Letter to Grover H. Perry from A.S. Embree, 2pp, 6/26/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 14. Letter to Grover H. Perry from A.S. Embree, 2pp, 7/26/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 15. Letter to Grover H. Perry from from William D. Haywood, 2pp, 7/6/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 16. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Jos. Oatis, 3pp, 7/6/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 17. Memo from Grover H. Perry, 1p, 6/1/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 18. Letter to F.H. Little from Sec'y Treas., 3pp, 4/11/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 19. Letter to Chas. H. MacKinnon from Sec'y Treas., 2pp, 6/5/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 20. Letter to Fellow Workers from Sec'y Treas., 2pp, 7/10/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 21. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Roger S. Culver, 2pp, 4/15/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 22. Letter to Grover H. Perry from J. MacDonald, 1p, 7/23/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 23. Letter to Geo Maddox from Jack F. Norman, 2pp, 8/7/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 24. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Jack Norman, 3pp, 7/23/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 25. Letter to Grover H. Perry from M.C. Sullivan, 3pp (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 26. Letter to Grover H. Perry from E.J. MacCasham, 4pp, 6/19/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 27. Letter to Grover H. Perry from J. McDonald, 1p, 6/27/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 28. Letter to Grover H. Perry from E.J. MacCasham, 4pp, 7/1/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 29. Letter to Grover H. Perry from E.J. MacCasham, 3pp, 7/6/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 30. Letter to Grover H. Perry from T.R. Wilson, 2pp, 7/9/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Salt Lake Exhibit 31. Letter to Grover H. Perry from E.J. MacCasham, 8pp, 4/21/1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- State of Arizona vs. H. Walters. Depositions [Watt, Wasson], 1916-1919
  - Deposition No. 2864: Depositions of Watt and Wasson, by Jon E. Orr, Notary Public, 42pp, 12/12/1919 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Deposition agreement No. 2684 from Watt and Wasson, by Court Clerk, 3pp, 12/11/1919 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Telegram to Governor Campbell from Sheriff Wheeler, 1p, 6/30/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letter to H.C. Wheeler from Hopkins, 1p, 6/5/1916 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 1. Letter to Don Sheridan from William D. Haywood, 2pp, 3/21/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 2. Letter to William D. Haywood from Sec'y Treas., 1p, 3/26/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 3. Letter to James Rowan from William Hardy, 1p, 5/21/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 4. Letter to William Hardy from Sec'y Treas., 1p, 5/23/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 5. Letter to Frover H. Perry from Sec'y Treas., 1p, 4/11/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 6. Letter to Grover H. Perry from Sec'y Spokane I.W.W., 1p, 4/17/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 7. Letter to James Rowan from Jos. Ratti, 1p, 5/22/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 8. Letter to Jos. Ratti from Sec'y Industrial Union #500, 1p, 5/24/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 9. Minutes Book front sheet, Special Business Meeting, by William Hardy, 3pp, 4/6/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 10. Minutes: Special Business Meeting, by H. Grant, 3pp, 3/18/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Exhibit 11. Minutes: Lumberworkers Convention, 4pp, 3/4-3/6/1917 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Simmons vs. El Paso and Southwestern Rail Road Depositions [Sheehan, Klein, Barry, Cahill, Quinn, Furbershaw, Lutz, Hughes, Wilder]. Acknowledgements of Service., 1919
  - Depositions No. 2364, by Edward J. Walsh, Court Reporter, 364pp, 10/29/1919 (Box 2, Folder 5)